<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://smithsafetygroup.ca/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://smithsafetygroup.ca/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://smithsafetygroup.ca/blogs/news.atom"/>
  <title>Smith Safety Group - News</title>
  <updated>2021-04-19T10:49:46-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Smith Safety Group</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://smithsafetygroup.ca/blogs/news/ppe-101</id>
    <published>2021-04-19T10:49:46-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-13T15:55:31-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://smithsafetygroup.ca/blogs/news/ppe-101"/>
    <title>PPE 101</title>
    <author>
      <name>Metroland Media</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>Having the right type of security can relieve you of additional stress. If you’re not sure about what the right PPE for your business needs are, click<strong> "Read More"</strong> to continue. </span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://smithsafetygroup.ca/blogs/news/ppe-101">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In an earlier blog post, we explored the importance of having a safe work environment upon re-entering the workforce. Having a solid game plan on how to keep both workers and customers alike protected as we get into the groove of a new normal can ease your mind in ensuring that your business stays safe. If you were not able to check out that article - you can check it out here. We’re sure you’ll gain some great ideas on how to create the best plan for your business. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While having a plan is wonderful, choosing the right type of protection can make or break your workplace plan. With the way rules and regulations are ever-changing as we adapt to these uncertain times, having the right type of security can relieve you of additional stress. If you’re not sure about what the right PPE for your business needs are, we can help! </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is the employer’s responsibility to provide PPE to the employees. Many employers provide a certain amount of money for the employee to buy their own PPE, and others provide PPE directly to their employees. Whichever way you decide to go with your PPE policy, it is legally the employer’s responsibility to provide PPE to ensure the safety of their employees.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Personal Protective Equipment (PPE) are items worn to provide a barrier to help prevent potential exposure to infectious disease. These items include:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gloves</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gowns</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Surgical masks</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Surgical masks with visor attachment</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Respirators</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Face shields</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Eye protection</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Goggles</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The N95 respirator mask is the U.S./NIOSH standard for respirators and KN95 is the Chinese standard. Commercial-grade (non-medical) and medical-grade N95 and KN95 respirators are similar with respect to design, filtration, performance and material standards. In Canada, it is the labelling, indications for use and claims that contribute to the classification of a product as a medical device.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Certified respirators must pass minimum performance requirements, such as:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">fit testing</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">filter efficiency</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">breathing resistance</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our</span><a href="https://smithsafetygroup.ca/products/n95-mask"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> N95</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> respirators, that are made in partnership with First Nations People in Canada, not only pass performance requirements They also support the Canadian Cancer Society with a percentage of each sale - check out more details about our N95 Mask </span><a href="https://smithsafetygroup.ca/pages/n95-masks"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now that you know what type of PPE can be included in your work safety plan, let’s talk about some best tips on using your personal protective equipment the right way!</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><b>Tip #1: Keep in Mind Fit and Comfort</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once it’s been decided that some protective equipment is essential to protect yourself or others in your workspace, then it must always be used to ensure everyone’s safety. It’s a non-negotiable and if your protection gear isn’t quite fitting the way they need to be, then the protection aspect of the item is greatly reduced. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An oversized pair of safety goggles or a face shield that barely fits properly aren’t going to be much use; take into consideration your employees sizing and comfort levels. For example, if someone wears glasses, then the safety goggles must account for enough space to accommodate their glasses. Their PPE doesn’t have to be perfectly form-fitting, but it shouldn’t be baggy. </span></p>
<br>
<p style="text-align: center;"><b>Tip #2 - There is a safe way to put on your PPE</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Please note that PPE does not reduce the hazard itself nor does it guarantee permanent or total protection but it can aid in your continued workplace safety plan. One thing to keep in mind is how PPE is put on - keeping all of your safety equipment safe while putting it on is key. Here are some things to keep in mind:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before putting on your PPE, clean your hands using soap and water or hand sanitizer.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">For respirators and masks that have a nosepiece, it should be fitted to the nose with both hands, not bent or tented. Do not pinch the nosepiece with one hand.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your respirator/face mask should be extended under the chin. Both your mouth and nose should be protected. Do not wear a respirator/face mask under your chin or store in your pockets between uses. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re using a respirator, please ensure that the straps are placed on the crown of head (top strap) and base of neck (bottom strap). Perform a user seal check each time you put on the respirator.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When wearing a face shield or goggles in addition to a N95 respirator, select the proper eye protection to ensure that the respirator does not interfere with the correct positioning of the eye protection, and that the eye protection does not affect the fit or seal of the respirator. Face shields provide full face coverage. Goggles also provide excellent protection for eyes, but fogging is common.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If wearing gloves, they should cover your wrist up to where the cuff of a long sleeve shirt would be.</span></li>
</ul>
<div style="text-align: center;"><b>Tip #3: Removing your PPE safely is just as important</b></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><b>  </b></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><b></b></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><b></b></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s important to know how to remove protective personal equipment in order to avoid transmission. Here is the best way to remove your PPE:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ensure glove removal does not cause additional contamination of hands. Gloves can be removed using more than one technique (e.g., glove-in-glove or bird beak).</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Perform hand hygiene using soap and water or hand sanitizer after removing gloves.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Carefully remove face shield or goggles by grabbing the strap and pulling upwards and away from head. Do not touch the front of the face shield or goggles.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Remove and discard respirator (or facemask if used instead of respirator). Do not touch the front of the respirator or facemask.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Perform hand hygiene after removing the respirator/face mask and before putting it on again if your workplace is practicing reuse.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you need some assistance in choosing the right bundles for your workforce, no matter the size, we’re here to help. We understand that choosing the right PPE is crucial for the health of your business so please feel free to contact us </span><a href="https://smithsafetygroup.ca/pages/contact-us"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, fill out the form and we’ll get back to you!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> <a href="https://smithsafetygroup.ca/pages/contact-us"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0466/2529/2438/files/SSG_Logo_Gold_white_140x_2x_473bc242-b8fc-4a9b-8da4-ea980cc2f33e_480x480.jpg?v=1614012480" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="164" height="98"></a></span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://smithsafetygroup.ca/blogs/news/do-you-have-a-safe-plan-for-re-entering-the-workforce</id>
    <published>2021-04-06T16:44:10-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-13T15:54:36-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://smithsafetygroup.ca/blogs/news/do-you-have-a-safe-plan-for-re-entering-the-workforce"/>
    <title>DO YOU HAVE A SAFE PLAN FOR RE-ENTERING THE WORKFORCE?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Metroland Media</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With vaccines rolling out for 2021, businesses that have been vacant, for the better part of 2020, are now preparing to re-enter the workplace and making it as safe as possible. As the Ministry of Labour, Training, and Skills Development says, “All workers have the right to return home each day safe and sound” and having a safe workplace plan to limit transmission or exposure to COVID dangers is imperative. </span></p>
<p>So if you’re wondering what your work space needs to do in order to protect your employees or aid your employer in keeping your team safe, we’ve got you covered! Here are some steps you can take to build out your safety plan.</p>
<br>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Step #1: Increase Your Screening</strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first step would be to put a screening plan in place to ensure that anyone entering your work space is healthy enough to not endanger others. You can download </span><a href="https://covid-19.ontario.ca/download-covid-19-screenings#worker-and-employee-screening"><span style="font-weight: 400;">this link</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for the Service Ontario Screening PDF in French or English for your employees. If your work space is opening to include customers, you can also use </span><a href="https://covid-19.ontario.ca/download-covid-19-screenings#customer-screening"><span style="font-weight: 400;">this</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Service Ontario Customer Screening PDF for your customers as well, available in both languages.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While these screenings are helpful, they cannot diagnose someone. If you have medical questions, consult a healthcare provider and follow along their guidelines. Be prepared for when workers must self-isolate to rescreen anyone they’ve been exposed to to ensure that others are taking the same precautions. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Step #2: Ensure Social Distancing </strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keeping your distance from others is crucial at these times; to ensure social distancing; you can implement some of the following tips:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Limit the amount of people in your space - maybe at the beginning of re-entering the workplace, limit it to a certain percentage of your team and rotate it on a non-conflicting schedule. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you have customers in store, limit it as well to a certain percentage while lineups can happen outside the door. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use a thermometer to ensure that symptoms like fever can be checked before entering any workspace.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keep a distance of two metres between people.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Assign workers to workstations that are at least two metres apart to ensure that the social distancing is happening with the workers as well. </span></li>
</ul>
<br>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can find some of our products handy in keeping your business safe, like our </span><a href="https://smithsafetygroup.ca/collections/thermometer/products/infrared-thermometer-1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">thermometer</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, our anti-fog worker </span><a href="https://smithsafetygroup.ca/collections/shop-all/products/safety-glasses-with-anti-fog-lenses"><span style="font-weight: 400;">glasses</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and our standing hand sanitizer </span><a href="https://smithsafetygroup.ca/collections/automatic-dispenser/products/floor-mount-automatic-hand-sanitizer-dispenser-does-not-ship-till-july-30th"><span style="font-weight: 400;">dispensers</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<br>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Step #3: Wear the Right Protection</span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wearing a mask is critical indoors; ensuring that your employees are provided instruction to wear masks properly and constantly is of the utmost importance. The supervision to ensure all workers wear masks also includes rules for while eating and drinking. If you’d like to review what the exact protocols are for your industry, you can review the precaution guidelines </span><a href="https://www.ontario.ca/page/resources-prevent-covid-19-workplace#section-0"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for your preferred sector. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Masks worn as PPE are meant to protect the people wearing them. We offer high-quality medical grade masks like </span><a href="https://smithsafetygroup.ca/products/n95-mask"><span style="font-weight: 400;">N95</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> masks that provide you with a better fit and better protection. They are also approved for use in healthcare and for workplace safety, while filtering ≥ 95% of airborne particles. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A mask should securely cover the nose and mouth and fit closely to the face without gaps. A nose piece that can be molded to conform to the face may be helpful to ensure a close fit.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Using a mask should not introduce any new health or safety hazards into the workplace such as masks getting caught in machinery or restricting vision.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When choosing what type of mask to use in your workplace, consider:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The purpose of the mask (source control and/or personal protection equipment)</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mask qualities that impact your workers’ ability to wear it when needed, for as long as needed (for example, breathability, comfort and durability)</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another workplace step would be to ventalize and sanitize repeatedly; consider the policies and procedures you can put in place to make sure you are cleaning and disinfecting and keeping the workplace as free of the virus as possible. The public health recommendation is to clean and disinfect high-touch surfaces at least thrice a day. </span></p>
<p>Air out the spaces around you as the transmission risk is higher in more enclosed and crowded spaces. Coming up with a safety plan to keep your workers and customers safe is pivotal in keeping people healthy but while you can take all of the precautions in the world, people can still get affected.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Contact your local public health unit for guidance on what to do if someone develops symptoms at your workplace or you are told one of your workers has COVID-19. Public health will provide instructions and do contact tracing if needed. To support contact tracing, have a system in place so you can provide information about which people had close interactions with an affected worker. This could include information such as:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dates and times of interactions</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Approximate length and frequency of interactions</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Full names</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Contact telephone numbers</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Addresses (for workers) or the name of the visitor’s business</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you need additional information on creating the best workspace plan, you can check out the complete rulebook </span><a href="https://www.ontario.ca/page/develop-your-covid-19-workplace-safety-plan"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If you don’t know where to start in purchasing wholesale PPE equipment, we’re here to help! Click on the Contact Us page </span><a href="https://smithsafetygroup.ca/pages/contact-us"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, fill out the form and we’ll get back to you! </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><a href="https://smithsafetygroup.ca/pages/contact-us"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0466/2529/2438/files/SSG_Logo_Gold_white_140x_2x_473bc242-b8fc-4a9b-8da4-ea980cc2f33e_480x480.jpg?v=1614012480" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="167" height="100"></span></a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
